# Matt Jones

### Software Developer

hello@mttjns.co.uk | mttjns.co.uk | github.com/matt-j-jones | linkedin.com/in/mattjosephjones | London NW5 | 07766257577

#### SUMMARY

A Project Manager with seven years of experience making a change to working in tech, I have recently completed a software development bootcamp at Makers Academy, and a master's degree in Game Design at Goldsmiths, University of London, where I achieved a final grade of 75% (1st class). I have experience using Python, Ruby, C#, JavaScript and TypeScript to develop projects individually and within teams. I have utilised my skill set to deliver diverse projects ranging from web applications to game development and AI integration.

#### **SKILLS**

Python, Flask, Pytest, Ruby, RSpec, Sinatra, Typescript, JavaScript, Jest, React, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, NoSQL, RESTful API, Express, Node, Cypress, C#, Unity, C++, OpenFrameworks, Jupyter Notebook, TypeScript, Lua, HTML5, CSS, Azure, Postgres, AutoCAD, Solidworks, Project Management, Project Planning, Agile, AI

#### **EDUCATION**

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp - Makers Academy, March 2023 to June 2023

- Utilising Ruby, Python and Javascript and practising Test-Driven Development (TDD) with RSpec, Pytest and Jest
- Developing responsive user interfaces using JavaScript, React, and CSS.
- Managing code version control with Git and GitHub to maintain code integrity.
- Designing and implementing scalable CRUD (Create, Read, Update, Delete) applications using the MERN (MongoDB, Express, React, Node) stack.
- Actively participating in pairing sessions with colleagues to effectively problem-solve, ideate and realise projects.
- Collaborating with different teams to build web applications in an Agile software development environment.

Master of Arts Independent Games and Playable Experience Design (75% - 1st Class MA) - Goldsmiths, September 2021 to September 2023

- Developing projects that focus on narrative game design in Unity using C#.
- Utilising C++ in OpenFrameworks for creative computing and Arduino physical computing projects.
- Using ML5.js and P5.js libraries to implement machine learning algorithms and creative coding into projects.

#### **COURSES**

Python Basics for Data Science - IBM: Using Python and Pandas to analyse and visualise data in a Jupyter Notebook.

CS50G Introduction to Game Development - HarvardX: Creating 2D and 3D games using PyGame, Kaboom.js, Lua, and Unity.

Google IT Automation with Python Professional Certificate - Google/Coursera.

Certificate in Responsive Web Design - FreeCodeCamp: Using HTML and CSS to make responsive web projects.

**AgilePM Practitioner - SPOCE** 

AutoCAD 2D Level 3 - City & Guilds

## **PROJECTS**

Name	Description	Tech/Tools
The London Underground Orchestra	An interactive front-end web application that uses the TfL API to convert live train arrival data into an engaging audio and visual experience. The application retrieves train arrival information from the API and sonifies it by mapping it to the underground network. Each station is assigned a music note, and each underground line is assigned an instrument. Project Link	Javascript, Tone.js, React, Node
Moangoose	A Twitter-like full-stack CRUD web application that enables users to create accounts, post 'moans' and comment on other 'moans'. The information is stored on a linked database that stores user information, posts, and comments. <a href="Project Link">Project Link</a>	Javascript, MongoDB, Express, React, Node
"Me, The Machine, and Edgar"	A Unity 2D Game Project where I collaborated with a machine-learning model. I trained the model on the complete works of Edgar Allan Poe and used it as a collaborative partner to create a new and unique story and game based on the works of Poe. The project aimed to provoke discussion on the concept of authorship in the era of artificial intelligence. Project Link	C#, Javascript, Python, Unity, ML5.js, P5.js, Style Transfer, Generative Text WebGL
Storyteller Dice	A front-end web application that blends random probability and AI language generation. It dynamically generates six images from a diverse pool of thirty-six options and leverages the GPT3.5 API to produce unique stories based on the selected images. Project Link	Javascript, JSX, React, GPT3.5 Generative AI Text, REST API

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Project Manager - Engineering Control Supplies, April 2019 to Present

Developing and maintaining project timelines and client relations, creating manufacturing quotes, collaborating with engineers and subcontractors, working closely with different teams and stakeholders, forecasting and preventing potential delays, and managing the delivery of projects using the Waterfall framework, as well as building and implementing tools and scripts into the in-house system to automate simple tasks to increase efficiency.

CAD & Planning Coordinator - Russell Cawberry, June 2017 to March 2019

Maintaining project version control, providing support to bid managers for refurbishment tendering at the UCLH and Kingston Hospitals, liaising with architects and on-site project managers, updating and managing project drawing packs, ensuring stakeholder access to up-to-date information, delivering high-quality 2D CAD drawings and facilitating smooth project delivery.

Design Project Manager - Special Projects, January 2014 to June 2017

Leading design and development of a new product line for a precision engineering company, submitting bids, attending project briefings, meeting with customers, collaborating with a small team of designers, engineers, and contractors, and facilitating the successful delivery of projects within allocated resources and timelines.